<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://lizhe-li.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://lizhe-li.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-02-08T05:22:26+00:00</updated><id>https://lizhe-li.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A researcher concerned with the relationship between human and machine communication. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://lizhe-li.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://lizhe-li.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lizhe-li.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Diagrams</title><link href="https://lizhe-li.github.io/blog/2021/diagrams/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Diagrams"/><published>2021-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lizhe-li.github.io/blog/2021/diagrams</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lizhe-li.github.io/blog/2021/diagrams/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <p>layout: post title: Artificial intelligence and communication: A Human–Machine Communication research agenda date: 2023-10-19 17:39:00 tags: formatting diagrams description: Guzman’s article on human-computer communication</p> <p>Artificial intelligence and people’s interactions with it—through virtual agents,socialbots, and language-generation software—do not fit neatly into paradigms of communication theory that have long focused on human–human communication. To address this disconnect between communication theory and emerging technology, this article provides a starting point for articulating the differences between communicative AI and previous technologies and introduces a theoretical basis for navigating these conditions in the form of scholarship within human–machine communication. Drawing on an HMC framework, we outline a research agenda built around three key aspects of communicative AI technologies: 1 the functional dimensions through which people make sense of these devices and applications as communicators, 2 the relational dynamics through which people associate with these technologies and, in turn, relate to themselves and others, and 3 the metaphysical implications called up by blurring ontological boundaries surrounding what constitutes human, machine, and communication.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[layout: post title: Artificial intelligence and communication: A Human–Machine Communication research agenda date: 2023-10-19 17:39:00 tags: formatting diagrams description: Guzman’s article on human-computer communication]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Code</title><link href="https://lizhe-li.github.io/blog/2015/code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Code"/><published>2015-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lizhe-li.github.io/blog/2015/code</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lizhe-li.github.io/blog/2015/code/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <p>layout: post title: What is Human-Machine Communication, Anyway? date: 2023-10-19 15:09:00 description: Guzman’s article on human-computer communication tags: formatting code categories: sample-posts featured: true</p> <p>This edited volume introduces readers to the growing area of Human-Machine Communication research within the communication discipline. As defined within this chapter, HMC is the creation of meaning between humans and machines, with technology theorized as a communicator, a subject with which people communicate, instead of a channel through which humans interact with one another. HMC research focuses on the process of communication between human and machine and the implications of encounters between people and technology for individuals, society, and humanity. HMC envelopes communication research within HumanComputer Interaction, Human-Robot Interaction, and Human-Agent Interaction while at the same time is inclusive of philosophical, critical/cultural, and related approaches regarding the integration of social technologies into everyday spaces. This introduction outlines the fundamental aspects of HMC by answering key questions regarding HMC’s historical and theoretical origins, the rationale for its establishment, and the nature of its research. This chapter highlights how deeply entrenched communication research has been within an anthropomorphic paradigm and how much work is yet to be done toward understanding what it means for people to communicate with robots, artificial intelligence, conversational agents, algorithms, and other emerging technologies.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[layout: post title: What is Human-Machine Communication, Anyway? date: 2023-10-19 15:09:00 description: Guzman’s article on human-computer communication tags: formatting code categories: sample-posts featured: true]]></summary></entry></feed>